## **ZUBAIR SHAIKH**

zsescape@gmail.com | 6097211763 | 17 Hamilton Lane, Plainsboro, NJ 08536 | linkedin.com/in/zsescape/ | github.com/compmonk

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Full Stack Engineer with 3+ years of experience of working on multiple projects involving multiple technologies. I can work with Django, Node JS, MVC.NET, React JS, Angular JS, Mongo DB and all the SQL databases. I have deployed projects on GCP and AWS. I have worked with Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas, Sklearn on my Data Science and Machine Learning projects involving image recognition, OCR, NLP, prediction and regression and classification. I'm a Hackathon enthusiast and like attending them to learn about new technologies and build new projects. I'm a Competitive Programmer and have attended and won many Programming and Coding competitions. I love code golfing and bug fixing against the time . I'm a 90+ level Pythonista on codesignal.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Developer, Black Bear Financial Technologies

Feb 2020 - May 2020

- Involved in planning and one of the founding members of Black Bear FT.
- Designed the System Architecture for the Black Bear Advisor Platform
- End to End development of the Black Bear Advisor Platform
- Worked on Django, Posgre SQL, Mongo DB, React JS
- Integrated third party tools and API for the Platform
- Setup the automated deployment pipeline

## Associate Software Engineer, Mediaocean

Jul 2017 - Dec 2018

- Worked on the Media Management Platform (Lumina) which was built in
- ASP.NET, MSSQL, MongoDB, jQuery, JS and ReactJS
- Solved different types of tasks which involved feature development, maintenance, bug fixing, writing one off scripts, database migrations, researching and finding solutions to different problems
- Involved in Sprint planning and brainstorming for feature development.
- $\bullet$  Part of the Everest team which completed the epic in 55% expected time
- Well versed with the Agile Software Development Life cycle framework
- Collaborated with teams from different continents.
- Successfully completed Mediaocean Boot Camp

# Full Stack Engineer, Consultant/ Freelancing

Jul 2016 - Present

- Customised CRM and ERP models for moving local business to cloud
- End to End Website solutions right from designing to cloud deployment
- Built numerous projects on Django, React JS, Angular JS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Built model of web scrapping based on BeautifulSoup Api in Python and additional Natural Language processing layer to create structured and querable cloud hosted database instance with MongoDB
- Job-candidate matching, Candidate-Job Matching, Resume Parser projects using NLP and collaborative recommendation and ranking
- REST API for end to end to create, run, and trigger data models and data sets.
- Developed AI enabled CRM integration tools
- Web Scraping and Analysis: Scraped data from websites
- using Beautiful Soup and analysed text data using nltk.
- Fraud Data Classifier: Used pandas for data modelling
- and Logistic Regression from scikit and numpy to find Fraud
- Transactions for an e-commerce website and visualised data using matplotlib
- Risk Score Analysis: Developed a web app in Django from
- end to end and used scikit for risk score analysis for a Credit Finserve data set.
- Image Recognition: A mobile app to recognise an image
- and show results using Django and Tensorflow

## PROJECTS

## Customized need based News website (The Syndicate Herald)

• The Syndicate Herald is a news aggregator website, that will show your daily customized news feeds. This website will gather news from https://newsapi.org/ API endpoints and will showcase the daily news for a user. A user can login into this website and choose his source preferences (news channels) and he will see the latest feed pulled up for him according to his preferences. Each news article will have a title, description and a link to read further about the news article. Furthermore he can search for news articles containing keywords.

## Car Repair Order and Management Tool (CarRO)

• Car Repair Order and Management Tool is a CRM for car service stations to add repair order to add and manage repair orders in workflows like Ordered, Repairing, Repaired, Reviewing and Done. This project won the best use of MongoDB Atlas at Hack Princeton Fall 2019.

#### Wikipedia Search Engine (WikiFinder)

• A Wikipedia sourced search engine using Tries. This search engine uses a Trie as the Inverted Index file which stores the core information for a search engine. The Trie traces a keyword by finding an existing prefix and adding up the remaining characters not present in the path but present in the word.

## Automatic Code Evaluation and Scoring System

- I developed this project for the annual programming competition at Digital Renaissance 2017. This was a platform where the contestant could submit their C/C++ code and the system would compile and test the code with test cases and score the candidate and maintain the leader board for the competition.
- Reduced the manual effort for grading the candidate's code.
- Maintained the scores and displayed the leader board in realtime
- Removed disputes regarding time ties in submissions as each code submission had a time stamp
- Was scalable to use any Problem statement and format.

## CRM / ERP for Car rental business (City Cars and Coaches)

- I built a customized CRM plus ERP application for City Cars and Coaches an Executive Car and Chauffeur Rental Service for Corporate since 20 years
- The project involved multiple technologies working together along with custom business logic.
- The application is Saas website owned by City Cars and Coaches where the vendors and clients have separate logins to monitor and handle their resource.
- Some key features of the applications are Ride booking and workflow management, GPS tracking, Workflow status notifications, Billing and Taxing and client account management.
- The application is built in Django, React JS, MongoDB and other inter connecting technologies.
- The application uses GCP and MongoDB Atlas to provide scalability and timely availability for its clients.

## **EDUCATION**

Masters Science, Computer Science Stevens Institute of Technology Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering Modern Education Society' College of Engineering Jan 2019 - May 2020

Aug 2013 - Jun 2017

### **SKILLS**

Full Stack Engineer: django, reactjs, nodejs, javascript, mongodb, nosql, sql, c#, api, postman, frontend, backend, spa, test coverage, kotlin, data security, AWS, GCP, cloud, java, XML, XSLT, ASP.NET, MSSQL, box Data Science / Machine Learning: pandas, python, tensorflow, sklearn, keras, regression, prediciton, data wrangling, data cleaning